Stuart Sanders Correspondence WLU.Coll.0241
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
Stuart Sanders Correspondence
Inclusive 1918-1965
Bulk 1926-1934
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
Sanders, Stuart, II
Sanders, Irwin T. (Irwin Taylor)
Gooch, Richard Este
WLU.Coll.0241
1.2 Linear Feet
Biographical / Historical
Sanders is a Class of 1931 alumnus of Washington and Lee University and was a businessman in Richmond from 1931-1934.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of Sanders' correspondence to his parents regarding life at Washington and Lee University, including his participation in the Arcades Club fraternity (now Delta Upsilon), sports, classes, jobs, and the Lexington Presbyterian Church as well as comments on campus drinking and mention of his brother Irwin Sanders and friend Richard Gooch. Includes his correspondence during his job with his uncle, Stuart Sanders, in Richmond at Sanders Brothers from 1931-1934 with significant comments about the Depression years. Includes 16 photographs of family and friends.
College Students -- Alcohol use; Depressions; Fraternal organizations; College sports; College Students -- Social conditions; College Students; Washington and Lee University. Delta Upsilon; Lexington Presbyterian Church (Lexington, Va.); Washington and Lee University
- Mementos, 1918-1924; Washington and Lee University; 6 Item (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents
  This file consists of report cards, cards that certify class promotions from City Graded Schools, an excerpt from the Washington and Lee University Bulletin, and sketches.
- Correspondence, 1926-06-1926-08; United States. Congress. House; Sanders, Robert S.; Taylor, Mary Bell; 47 Item (Box 1, Folder 3)
  This file consists of letters and postcards mostly from Stuart Sanders to his parents. Stuart stayed with his Aunt for the summer, most likely somewhere near New York.
  Tennessee -- Sweetwater; United States Senate Chamber (United States Capitol, Washington, D.C.); North America -- Niagara Falls; New York (State) -- Canandaigua; Washington (DC); Sanders, Irwin T. (Irwin Taylor)
- Correspondence, 1927-06-1927-07; 22 Item (Box 1, Folder 4)
  This file consists of letters written from Stuart Sanders to his parents while he was at summer school at The McCallie School in Chattanooga, Tennessee.
  Correspondence; Summer schools; McCallie School (Chattanooga, Tenn.); Sanders, Robert S.
- College Applications, 1927-05-1927-09; Sanders, Robert S.; Easter, De La Warr Benjamin; 20 Item (Box 1, Folder 5)
  This file contains mostly letters written by Robert Sanders concerning his son Stuart's college applications. He wrote to the presidents at the University of Florida and at Washington and Lee University, where Stuart's broter was a student. Washington and Lee granted Stuart a tentative place on their list of students, requiring he complete more credits in summer school. Upon completion of summer school at The McCallie School, Stuart was admitted officially to Washington and Lee.
  College admission officers; Stuart, Robert, D.D.; University of Florida; Smith, Henry Louis; McCallie School (Chattanooga, Tenn.)
- Correspondence During First Term at Washington and Lee, 1927-09-1927-11; Washington and Lee University; Young Men's Christian Associations of North America; Howe, James Lewis; 50 Item (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Stuart writes to his parents with news of football, his studies, and his desire for a typewriter. His report card is also included.
  Correspondence; Sanders, Robert S.; Sanders, Stuart, II; Sanders, Irwin T. (Irwin Taylor); Clark, John Craig; Washington and Lee University. Arcades Fraternity
- Correspondence, 1927-12-1928-02; Sanders, Robert S.; Sanders, Stuart, II; Sanders, Irwin T. (Irwin Taylor); Mattingly, Earl Stansbury; 45 Item (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Correspondence from Stuart to his parents about his second term at Washington and Lee.
  Crenshaw, Ollinger; Ewing, Boyd Ross, Jr.; Smith, Livingston Waddell; Morton, William Wilson; Fletcher, Forest; Washington and Lee University
- Correspondence, 1928-03-1928-04; Sanders, Stuart, II; Sanders, Robert S.; 46 Item (Box 1, Folder 8)
  This file mostly contains letters from Stuart home to his parents during his last months of his first year at Washington and Lee. It also includes correspondence between Dr. Smith and Robert Sanders about Stuart's poor math grades.
  Smith, Livingston Waddell
- Correspondence, 1928-05-1928-06; Taylor, Mary Bell; Sanders, Stuart, II; 22 Item (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Stuart writes about his final exams and grades, plans for the summer, and courses for his second year at Washington and Lee.
  Sanders, Robert S.
- Correspondence, Summer 1938, 1938-06-1938-08; Mattingly, Earl Stansbury; Sanders, Irwin T. (Irwin Taylor); Ellard, Roscoe B.; Sanders, Stuart, II; 38 Item (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Stuart writes home from his aunt's house in Canandaigua, NY, where he is for the summer.
  New York (State) -- Canandaigua; Taylor, Mary Bell
- Correspondence, 1928-09-1928-10; Sanders, Stuart, II; 33 Item (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Stuart writes about his brother, a new suit, school, sports, etc.
  Sanders, Robert S.; Sanders, Irwin T. (Irwin Taylor)
- Correspondence, 1928-11-1928-12; Sanders, Stuart, II; 30 Item (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Sanders, Irwin T. (Irwin Taylor); Sanders, Robert S.
- Correspondence, 1929-01-1929-03; Sanders, Stuart, II (Box 2, Folder 14)
  This file consists of letters from Stuart to his parents and newspaper clippings.
- Correspondence, 1929-04-1929-07; Washington and Lee University; Sanders, Stuart, II; Mattingly, Earl Stansbury; 43 Item (Box 2, Folder 15)
  This file consists of correspondence between Stuart and his parents. It also consists of commencement material, where Irwin was the valedictorian. Stuart's letter to the president of the school applying for reinstatment (because of lack of credits) and the dean's response are included. Stuart was reinstated on strict probation.
  Correspondence; Commencement ceremonies; Sanders, Irwin Taylor, II; Sanders, Robert S.; Smith, Henry Louis
- Printed Matter and Photograph, 1928-1929; Washington and Lee University. Arcades Fraternity; Randolph-Macon Woman's College; Washington and Lee University; 18 Item (Box 2, Folder 16)
  This file consists of student publications mentioning Stuart and a photograph of Stuart in his track uniform. In the Ring Tum Phi there is an announcement of his election to head cheer leader. There are also campaign cards in the file. Newspapers from Sweetwater, TN and Memphis, TN wrote articles about Robert S. Sanders. And there are Arcades Club and Randolph Macon Woman's College bulletins.
  Newspapers; Tennessee -- Sweetwater; Tennessee -- Memphis
- Correspondence, 1929-08-1929-09; Sanders, Robert S.; Sanders, Stuart, II; Sanders, Stuart; 28 Item (Box 3, Folder 17)
  Correspondence during the beginning of Stuart's junior year at Washington and Lee. Stuart is living in the fraternity house at this time.
  Virginia -- Lexington; Virginia -- Lynchburg; Clark, John Craig; Gooch, Richard Este; Sanders, Irwin T. (Irwin Taylor)
- Correspondence, 1929-10-1929-11; Sanders, Stuart, II; 35 Item (Box 3, Folder 18)
  Virginia -- Lynchburg; Sanders, Irwin T. (Irwin Taylor); Sanders, Robert S.; Gooch, Richard Este; Washington and Lee University
- Correspondence, 1929-11-1929-12; Sanders, Stuart, II; 27 Item (Box 3, Folder 19)
  Virginia -- Lynchburg; Virginia -- Richmond; Gooch, Richard Este; Randolph-Macon Woman's College; Washington and Lee University. Arcades Fraternity; Washington and Lee University. Delta Upsilon; Cole, Betty; Sanders, Robert S.
- Correspondence, 1930-01-1930-02; Sanders, Stuart, II; Campbell, Henry Donald; Gooch, Virgo; Cole, Betty; 50 Item (Box 3, Folder 20)
  Virginia -- Lynchburg; Gooch, Richard Este; Sanders, Stuart; Easter, De La Warr Benjamin; Fletcher, Forest; Cole, Betty; Sanders, Irwin T. (Irwin Taylor); Sanders, Robert S.; Kelly, Howard A.
- Correspondence, 1930-03-1930-04; Virginia State Penitentiary; Sanders, Stuart, II; Cole, Betty; Sweets, Henry H.; Cole, Elizabeth; 51 Item (Box 3, Folder 21)
  This file consists of correspondence from Stuart to his parents, as well as a few letters from Betty to Stuart's parents. Campaign cards from Stuart's campaign for head cheerleader are included.
  Cheerleading; Sanders, Robert S.; Sanders, Stuart; Washington and Lee University. Delta Upsilon
- Correspondence, 1930-05-1930-09; Sanders, Stuart, II; Sanders, Irwin T. (Irwin Taylor); Gaines, Francis Pendleton; Cole, Betty; Gooch, Richard Este; Mattingly, Earl Stansbury; 27 Item (Box 3, Folder 22)
  Correspondence from summer 1930 before Stuart's senior year at Washington and Lee.
  Sanders, Stuart; Easter, De La Warr Benjamin
- Printed Materials, 1929-1930; Washington and Lee University; Washington and Lee University. Arcades Fraternity; 5 Item (Box 3, Folder 23)
  This file consists of two issues of the Ring Tum Phi, both mentioning the study body elections. Stuart ran for the position of head cheerleader. A 1931 Washington and Lee Alumni Magazine is included. There is also the Arcades Club publication, 'The Arcadian,' where Stuart and Irwin's pictures are featured. And Irwin's 'Bulgaria and the Holy Land' is in the file.
  Sanders, Irwin T. (Irwin Taylor); Sanders, Stuart, II
- Correspondence, 1930-09-1930-10; Sanders, Stuart, II; 29 Item (Box 4, Folder 24)
  This file consists of letters written by Stuart at the beginning of his senior year. He writes of his rocky relationship during this time with Betty. A program from the University Kentucky vs. Washington and Lee football game is also included.
  Sanders, Robert S.; Sanders, Stuart; Cole, Betty
- Correspondence, 1930-11-1930-12; Sanders, Stuart, II; 55 Item (Box 4, Folder 25)
  Sanders, Irwin T. (Irwin Taylor); Sanders, Robert S.; Easter, De La Warr Benjamin; Sanders, Stuart; Gooch, Richard Este; Lewis, Charles Irving; Clark, John Craig; Cole, Betty
- Correspondence, 1931-01-1931-02; Sanders, Stuart, II; 44 Item (Box 4, Folder 26)
  Gooch, Richard Este; Sanders, Stuart; Sanders, Robert S.; Clark, John Craig; Washington and Lee University. Delta Upsilon
- Correspondence, 1931-03; Sanders, Stuart, II; 25 Item (Box 4, Folder 27)
  Sanders, Robert S.; Gooch, Virgo; Gooch, Richard Este; Sanders, Irwin T. (Irwin Taylor)
- Correspondence, 1931-04-1931-06; Sanders, Stuart, II; Gooch, Richard Este; Sanders, Stuart; 65 Item (Box 4, Folder 28)
  This file consists of correspondence during he end of Stuart's senior year at Washington and Lee. It also consists of a baccalaureate program, a commencement program, a Finals Week Dances book and program.
- Correspondence, 1931-06-1931-12; Sanders, Stuart, II; 71 Item (Box 5, Folder 29)
  This file consists of correspondence from Staurt to his parents and family. At this time he was living in Richmond and working for his uncle at Sanders Brothers Company.
  Virginia -- Richmond; Sanders, Irwin T. (Irwin Taylor); Sanders, Robert S.; Gooch, Richard Este; Cole, Betty; Sanders, Stuart
- Correspondence, 1932-01-1932-04; Sanders, Stuart, II; Grace Covenant Presbyterian Church (Richmond, Va.); 41 Item (Box 5, Folder 30)
  Virginia -- Richmond; Sanders, Irwin T. (Irwin Taylor); Sanders, Robert S.; Sanders, Stuart; Cole, Betty; Landmark Theater (Richmond, Va.)
- Correspondence, 1932-05-1932-08; Sanders, Stuart, II; Cole, Betty; Gooch, Richard Este; 55 Megabytes (Box 5, Folder 31)
  Stuart writes to his parents with news of work and church in Richmond. He also writes of Irwin's trip back to America.
  Virginia -- Richmond; Gooch, Richard Este; Taylor, Mary Bell; Sanders, Irwin Taylor, II; Sanders, Robert S.; Grace Covenant Presbyterian Church (Richmond, Va.)
- Correspondence, 1932-09-1932-12; Sanders, Stuart, II; 36 Item (Box 5, Folder 32)
  Stuart writes about Irwin and his Uncle Stuarts health. Irwin is at Princeton at this time. He also writes to his Unlce Tom and Aunt Kathleen thanking them for the car they gave him and of his Christmas plans.
  Mallory, Dorothy; Gooch, Richard Este; Princeton University; Sanders, Irwin T. (Irwin Taylor); Sanders, Robert S.; Sanders, Stuart; Grace Covenant Presbyterian Church (Richmond, Va.); Sweets, Henry H.
- Correspondence, 1933-01-1933-04; Sanders, Stuart, II; 48 Item (Box 5, Folder 33)
  Stuart writes to his family about church, work, and his social life.
  Gooch, Richard Este; Sanders, Irwin Taylor, II; Sanders, Robert S.; Mallory, Dorothy; Grace Covenant Presbyterian Church (Richmond, Va.); Maitland, Isabelle
- Correspondence, 1933-05-1933-09; Sanders, Stuart, II; 55 Item (Box 5, Folder 34)
  Stuart writes letters to his parents, brother, and Dick about his social life, his relationship with Isabelle, and church.
  Sanders, Irwin T. (Irwin Taylor); Gooch, Richard Este; Sanders, Robert S.; Maitland, Isabelle
- Correspondence, 1933-10-1933-12; Sanders, Stuart, II; 48 Item (Box 5, Folder 35)
  Stuart writes to John M., his parents, Irwin, and Isabelle with news mostly of his church in Richmond and of his health. There are also a couple of letters from Isabelle to Stuart.
  Jones, John M.; Sanders, Irwin T. (Irwin Taylor); Maitland, Isabelle; Cornell University
- Correspondence, 1934-01-1934-03; Sanders, Stuart, II; 55 Item (Box 5, Folder 36)
  Stuart writes about work, church, and his dating life. He also writes about the passing of his cousin Lorraine.
  Virginia -- Richmond; Sanders, Irwin T. (Irwin Taylor); Sanders, Robert S.; Taylor, Mary Bell; Sanders, Stuart; Gooch, Richard Este; Grace Covenant Presbyterian Church (Richmond, Va.); Maitland, Isabelle; Cole, Betty
- Correspondence, 1934-04-1934-07; Sanders, Stuart, II; 35 Item (Box 5, Folder 37)
  Stuart writes to his parents, Betty, Dick, Irwin, and other family members about his life in Richmond. During these months Irwin got married.
  Sanders, Robert S.; Gooch, Richard Este; Sanders, Irwin T. (Irwin Taylor); Cole, Betty
- Newspaper Clippings, 1934; 33 Item (Box 5, Folder 38)
  This file consists of mostly newspaper clippings relating to Grace Covenant Presbyterian Church, Richmond, Va. There are also many clippings of young women who hosted teas. There are papers and questions about an article, 'What is an Education.'
  Sanders, Stuart, II; Grace Covenant Presbyterian Church (Richmond, Va.)
- The Scribbler, 1933-1934; Grace Covenant Presbyterian Church (Richmond, Va.); 34 Item (Box 5, Folder 39)
  The Scribbler is a newspaper tha was published weekly by the Young People's Forum of Grace Covenant Presbyterian Church, Richmond, Va.
  Publications
- Photographs, 1912-1937; 6 Item (Box 5, Folder 40)
  This file consists of phtographs from various years. There are xeroxed photographs from A Picture History of the Sanders Family, lent to Special Collections in 2000 by Irwin Taylor Sanders II, professor of history at Washington and Lee.
  Sanders, Stuart, II; Sanders, Irwin T. (Irwin Taylor); Maitland, Isabelle; Cole, Betty; Mallory, Dorothy; Minor, Jane; Sanders, Adelina Hall
- Miscellaneous, 1946-1965; Centre College (Danville, Ky.: 1918- ); Sanders, Stuart, II; 6 Item (Box 5, Folder 41)
  Items include:Receipt from Office Equipment Co., Louisville, Ky., 1945Washington and Lee Alumni Association of Richmond Washington-Cincinnati Day Banquet Program. Stuart was the president of the association at this time.Reconversion of Industry, April 1946A letter from StuartA commencement program from Centre College of Kentucky, 1965, when Irwin T. Sanders II was a graduate.
  Sanders, Irwin Taylor, II